MOHAMED ASIF OSMAN

FRONT END DEVELOPER

+2779 139 0499 / +2765 847 5289







www.osmanwebdesign.co.za



Durban, KZN, South Africa (Open to relocation)



View Github Profile

View Portfolio Online

technical skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

ReactJs

Vue

NextJs

NuxtJs

Git

Github

SQL

Bootstrap

Tailwind

Flutter

Jira

Figma

about me

An experienced web developer with a strong foundation in HTML, CSS, Javascript, libraries and frameworks. A highly skilled and adaptable professional with a strong foundation in technical skills and a range of interpersonal skills that allow to effectively collaborate, communicate, and solve problems in a team-oriented environment. A goal driven and highly motivated team player with potential to take on leadership responsibilities.

professional experience

2014 – CURRENT Frontend Developer Osman WD | Durban, South Africa

- Successfully engineered and built responsive web applications and eCommerce stores with advanced features and integrations.
- Skilled in translating design to code and implementing successful UX & UI design.
- Experience connecting to API services, working with headless
 CMS websites, and integrating with third-party payment gateways.
- Proficient in version control with Git and maintain a profile on GitHub with several repositories.
- Experience working with databases and the MySQL database software.
- Maintained front-end code for re-designs and production work.
- Assisted in the deployment of online marketing initiatives, including banner advertisements.
- Identified and implemented dynamic web solutions in accordance with client standards and best practices.
- Assisted a digital agency in developing WordPress sites, collaborating with design teams to take client wireframes from conception to implementation.
- Troubleshooting and updating throughout the production life cycle.
- Ensured projects complied with correct technology processes, industry best practices, and company standards.
- Conducted research and new business scoping efforts, resulting in the acquisition of new clients.
- Worked on projects in an Agile, collaborative environment to receive design requirements, peer program, and test applications.
- Proficient in digitising handbooks with tools that require authentication and a member dashboard.

jobs

PREVIOUS WORK EXPERIENCE

2012-2014

SBC Travel

Travel Office Manager

2010 -2012

Sure Mithas Travel

Groups Travel Consultant

2007-2010

Fidelity Super Care

Sales Executive

2005-2007

Precision Health Distributors

Sales Representative

2003-2005

Magpharm Pharmaceuticals

Sales Representative

education

TERTIARY LEVEL EDUCATION

CURRENT (3RD YEAR) | UNIVERSITY OF SOUTH AFRICA
Bachelor of Commerce Degree (Marketing Management)
Marketing 1,2, | Economics 1,2 | Consumer behavior |
Business Management 1,2,3 | Financial Accounting 1 | Public Relations

2005

VARSITY COLLEGE SCHOOL OF BUSINESS
Sales & Marketing | Management Certificate
Sales Management | Marketing Strategy | Advertising
Marketing Management| Branding

SECONDARY LEVEL EDUCATION

2002

WESTVILLE BOYS HIGH SCHOOL

Orient School

Matric Exemption (2002)

Subjects: English, Afrikaans, Biology, Maths, Geography,

Business Economics